[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 10]
Stop.
Grand Commander.
Madam instructed
that upon arrival,
all the lamps should be put out.
So...
Put them out.
Put out the lamps.
Grand Commander,
please watch your step.
-Grand Commander.
Grand Commander.
Miss Yan
has taken an unfamiliar man
to my chamber.
She asked us to wait here.
Mr. Han.
Where have you been
hiding all this time?
Why are you leaving so soon?
Han Shiyuan?
Shiyuan ran away.
Are you sure that person is Han Shiyuan?
It's him.
That's exactly how he ran away that day.
He was wearing the exact
same clothes.
Yes.
Exactly the same.
That day,
you were startled by the fire at the Ming Hall.
Plus, it was bright in the east and dark in the west,
and that person headed west.
That day,
you didn't
see his face clearly at all.
It wasn't him?
But it was clearly him just now.
It was also him that day.
The one in the room just now wasn't him,
and it wasn't him that day either.
It was his shadow.
That day,
Lan Guizhou used the shadow
to create the illusion that
Han Shiyuan was still in the house.
After that, he disguised himself as Han Shiyuan
and left, heading west.
Coincidentally,
the Ming Hall to the east caught fire,
producing a huge glow
that diverted attention,
resulting in
the witnessing student mistakenly believing
that he was Han Shiyuan.
You're making baseless assumptions.
On the seventh day of the fifth lunar month,
Shiyuan was clearly inside the house,
and then he left, heading west.
The thing is
both you
and the student
who witnessed outside
indicated that
Han Shiyuan
left the house alone.
You were inside the house.
In a situation where the lights were on inside
and it was dark outside,
how could you possibly see
Han Shiyuan heading west?
Miss Yan has a point.
With the lights on inside the house,
it's indeed impossible to see what's going on outside.
As for why he fabricated the story of
Han Shiyuan still being at the Hongwen Academy
on the night of the seventh day of the fifth lunar month,
that's a question
we should ask this good roommate of his.
Take him away.
Students, disperse.
Pan.
Thank you so much for today.
It was just a small trick,
not worth mentioning.
Who exactly is this Pan?
Look. Madam and he
are chatting and laughing,
as if they're old acquaintances.
Miss Yan.
I have other matters to attend to today,
so excuse me for not staying longer.
You're leaving already?
I haven't even had the chance
to thank you properly.
If it's meant to be, we'll meet again.
If you need anything in the future,
feel free to come find me at the Ghost Market anytime.
It's a deal.
Is that so?
Yes.
Madam has never been
so cheerful in the mansion.
Today, we really owe it to Pan
for successfully solving the case.
Are you going to the Imperial Security Bureau without me?
What about the interrogation?
Figure something out yourself.
What is that about?
Grand Commander, we've investigated.
That Pan is named Pan Chi.
He solved several mysterious cases in Jiangnan.
Grand Commander.
Shall we start the interrogation now?
If you want to ask or interrogate,
just go ahead.
Shut up.
Madam.
How's the interrogation going?
Madam, you're finally here.
We've been waiting for you.
Even if she crawled here, she should have arrived by now.
Hurry up and start the interrogation.
You thought
after Han Shiyuan eloped,
he wouldn't appear again,
so you fabricated his presence
to frame him for the murder?
Yes.
That's right.
Shiyuan said
he'd elope with his lover on the night of the sixth.
I didn't mean to harm Shiyuan.
I knew he was leaving.
I just wanted to use his name.
But this doesn't seem to be
your motive for murder, right?
Everything you said is about Han Shiyuan,
yet you never mentioned a word about
that student you killed.
You still haven't told me
why you committed that murder.
He?
What's there to say about him?
He damaged my poetry collection.
Didn't he deserve to die?
Just because
he damaged your poetry collection,
you killed your own classmate?
That poetry collection was very important to me.
Shiyuan
was my only friend.
[Han Shiyuan]
After Shiyuan and Yan Caiwei
started dating,
I stayed up many nights
to copy that poetry collection.
It was my gift to Shiyuan.
My poetry collection!
It was just a copied, worthless poetry collection.
Do you think you're Pan Yanzhi?
You think this crappy poetry collection
would actually be
treasured by someone?
Just a stack of waste paper.
My poetry collection.
How dare he destroy it?
And he even dared to mock me.
You committed murder
and deliberately framed Han Shiyuan for it.
Actually,
deep down, you were hoping for him
to come back when he heard the news.
After Han Shiyuan returned to Xiang'an,
he disappeared.
Have you seen him?
Where did you hide Han Shiyuan?
In an abandoned winery warehouse
in the West Market.
[The items displayed are all props made by the crew. No animals were harmed in the making of this drama.]
That Lan Guizhou
actually comes here regularly
to torture and kill animals.
His mind is so twisted.
No wonder he would develop the evil intention to kill
because of a poetry collection.
Han Shiyuan
has been snatched away again.
It's a signal sent by the Imperial Security Bureau.
In the direction of Furong Garden.
Shen Du!
Can't you just let me
sit properly on the horse?
[Furong Garden]
Hand.
Jing Lin.
My legs are a bit numb.
Can you help me down?
So stubborn.
Don't try to be a hero again.
Jing Lin.
Hurry up and save them.
I...
My third sister is up there.
Quickly, send the Imperial Guards to put out the fire and save her.
The case is abnormal.
We can't act rashly.
White Ghost, maybe you can disregard human life,
but I can't.
If you won't save them, I will.
Don't go over there.
Watch out!
It's the Cold Flame.
Here she comes.
Moths to a flame.
[Chen Huo'e]
Born at dawn, dead by dusk.
Not entering the cycle of reincarnation.
Immortal reincarnation.
Fools of the world.
I, Chen Huo'e,
have returned!
Chen Huo'e?
The serial killer from five years ago.
Didn't she
commit suicide in public five years ago?
The dead cannot be brought back to life.
Being so secretive and underhanded.
It must be a cover-up.
To think that someone,
facing the Nirvana formation of my rebirth,
could remain so calm and composed.
As expected from you, White Ghost.
Alas,
even if
you are a soul-reaping ghost official,
you cannot stop me, Chen Huo'e,
from being reborn.
Then I shall capture you, evil spirit,
and send you back to hell.
Caiwei.
Sister Caiwei.
Han.
Xing.
Grand Commander.
Administer Yang, you're here.
It seems that
Princess Yong'an will be the one
inquiring about this matter.
However, the Grand Empress Dowager's
Qianniu Guards also got involved.
It's indeed
a bit perplexing.
This...
Prince Ying
only ordered me to save Mr. Han.
As for the rest,
I don't know either.
Grand Commander. Administer Yang.
I was in a haste to save them. I apologize for my abruptness.
I hope I haven't interrupted your business.
No wonder
you managed to mobilize
the sword-bearing Qianniu Guards serving the Grand Empress Dowager.
So it's you,
the favored one by the Grand Empress Dowager,
Deputy Minister Zhang.
Shiyuan.
You...
How did you end up like this?
Are you hurt?
Are you alright?
Never mind, never mind.
As long as you're safe.
You must remember
to be more careful in the future.
Don't let yourself
get into such a predicament again.
Grand Commander Shen.
What happened today was unusual.
Fortunately, you were here.
Please ask the Imperial Security Bureau
to pay more attention to this matter in the future.
You must catch
the mastermind behind this
to avoid future troubles.
This matter was originally
the responsibility of the Imperial Security Bureau.
If you two hadn't been so hasty,
the culprit would have already been brought to justice.
In the heat of the moment,
we may have caused offense.
I hope you can forgive us, Grand Commander.
The reappearance of Chen Huo'e
is quite odd.
As for catching the culprit,
we'll have to rely on you, Grand Commander.
I have to return to the palace and get back to my duties.
I'll take my leave now.
Han Shiyuan.
Her Highness asked me to relay a message to you.
As long as you're willing, Mr. Han,
Her Highness's feelings haven't changed.
Han Shiyuan.
About tonight's events,
do you have anything you want to say?
I know nothing about it.
Regarding the case of the murdered student of Hongwen Academy,
Xing has already
cleared you of suspicion.
Tonight,
you and Yan Caiwei are victims.
If you have nothing else to say,
hurry up and take her back
to Yan's Mansion to recover.
[Furong Garden]
This third brother-in-law of yours
surprisingly has close relationships
with both Princess Yong'an
and Zhang Baohuan.
It's quite unexpected.
Indeed.
Obviously, Han Shiyuan and Zhang Baohuan
have known each other for a long time.
He also has quite a history with Princess Yong'an.
But now that they saved him,
he showed no gratitude at all.
If he could, he would even pretend not to know them.
There must be a reason for this.
But my third sister
seems to genuinely
know nothing about it.
I know.
From the beginning,
I never intended
to make things difficult for your third sister.
Sorry for
being rash just now.
Later, I'll go
to the Ministry of Justice to check the case files.
Do you...
want to come along?
Yes.
I'll go.
[Furong Garden]
Come on, guys.
Put two inside.
And place two more here.
By the door.
Put two at each side of the door.
Make sure all the lanterns are aligned.
Light it up well for Grand Commander.
Clear out.
Isn't this a bit over the top?
You put up so many lanterns.
As if candles were free.
[Case File for Chen Huo'e's Multiple Murders in Several Locations]
Found it.
Five years ago,
the notorious Chen Huo'e committed crimes in multiple locations.
[Case File for Chen Huo'e's Multiple Murders in Several Locations]
She consecutively murdered
over 50 women.
And on the back of each deceased woman,
there was
a giant
fire-scorched moth mark.
The entire nation was gripped by panic.
All families with daughters
kept their doors closed and stayed inside.
Eventually,
the transgressor, Chen Huo'e,
was captured by the Imperial Investigation Department.
She turned out to be
an ugly woman.
She arrogantly claimed
that she knew the secret method of resurrection
and would eventually return.
Chen Huo'e drew her sword and severed her own heart vessels,
and died at the arrest scene.
Before she died,
she left one last sentence.
"Moths to a flame.
Born at dawn, dead by dusk."
Not entering the cycle of reincarnation.
Immortal reincarnation!
Moths to a flame!
Born at dawn, dead by dusk!
"Not entering the cycle of reincarnation.
Immortal reincarnation."
Mrs. Tang?
From the motives and methods
of these two cases,
they have no similarities at all.
But judging by the case details alone,
both of the two cases
couldn't have been done by one person.
So there's a gang.
Whether it's
Mrs. Tang's murder and burial,
or the multiple murders
committed by Chen Huo'e five years ago,
or even
tonight's mysterious act,
the Nirvana formation,
none of these could have been
accomplished by one person.
This isn't a simple gang operation.
Just based on tonight's events,
the relationships behind it are complex and intricate.
I'm afraid this Chen Huo'e
is also just a scapegoat.
So is the Chen Huo'e who showed up tonight
the same person as the one
who was brought to justice five years ago?
Whether it's the same person or not,
Chen Huo'e from five years ago
disappeared after committing the crime.
It indicates that the person behind it
no longer needed her.
However, five years later,
Chen Huo'e appeared again,
implying this person behind the scenes
has needs again.
Indeed.
What exactly does he want?
The situation behind this is complex and intricate.
A small mistake
could lead to a major disaster.
Mother.
The night-blooming jasmine in the backyard has blossomed.
I picked a bouquet
and brought it here for you.
Now that you're alone over there,
do you feel lonely?
How about
I sing a song for you?
Do you remember
the lullaby you used to sing to me
when I was little?
♫Speak not in vain♫
♫Grandma scolds♫
♫Mother picks flowers endlessly♫
♫Father listens to music with joy♫
Who's there?
It's the first time
I've heard someone singing nursery rhymes in a graveyard.
On this dark and windy night,
it's quite intriguing.
Oh, it's you.
Ghost Face, I've seen you before.
When I came to visit
my mother,
I often saw you around here.
Do you also have relatives buried nearby?
Yes.
My mother
is buried near here.
I had no idea
there were
other families' tombs in this area.
The auspicious burial grounds near Xiang'an City
have certainly been bought up
by noble families
and wealthy households for their final resting places.
Nameless spirits
can only curl up
in the corners of the cemetery,
begging for
an underground dwelling place.
[Tomb of Beloved Wife Wang Ruohan]
This burial plot
did cost my father
a fortune.
It's indeed very large and grand.
But I know
my mother
wouldn't want to be all alone
here by herself.
She must also hope
to make more friends.
So I guess
my mother and your mother
must have already become
good neighbors and friends, Ghost Face.
Good friends?
You are
somewhat different.
Why do you wear a mask?
Is it because your face is injured?
Since I was born,
I've had an ugly birthmark on my face.
Its shape is terrifying.
Those who have seen my face
are all frightened into having recurring nightmares.
Do you want to see it?
Just a moment.
Let me prepare myself mentally.
Can you wait while I count to five?
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Ghost Face?
He's left already?
Your hand hasn't been treated yet.
I asked Butler Shen
to bring all kinds of ointments
from the mansion.
Let's see which one is best for treating this...
Bite wound.
How did it get so serious?
I was bitten by a puppy.
It's nothing serious.
Butler Shen said
there's a kind of red ointment
that Yaya used before.
Being bitten by Yaya
should be similar
to being bitten by me.
Indeed.
Previously, Yaya
was bitten by a crazy dog.
It's indeed similar.
Is this your way of apologizing?
Why should I apologize?
It was because you didn't make yourself clear
that I misunderstood you.
Besides,
it's already been hours since you got injured tonight.
Why didn't you have
Jing Lin bandage it?
Why did you have to wait for me?
I...
Let go of me!
Let's go.
Let go!
Let go of me!
Du.
Even though you did that to save her,
you still need to be careful.
If that arrow just now
had been an inch higher,
this person would have certainly died.
Father,
I won't miss my shot.
We still need to keep him alive
for interrogation.
My name is Shen Du.
Are you alright?
Are you still
that boy I remember,
descending from the heavens like a divine soldier?
Who's that?
Yan Xing!
W-What? How could this be?
You did this on purpose, didn't you?
Of course not.
I'm sorry. I grabbed the wrong one.
[Jinchuang Powder] [Jinhuang Powder]
You...
I'll wash it off for you right away.
♫The night is still young, and the moonlight reflects on the west window♫
♫There are stars in your eyes♫
♫When I touch you♫
♫My heart is like a flickering candlelight, shaking and swaying♫
♫The more I care, the deeper I hide♫
♫Leaves turn yellow and fall, and my thoughts run in thousands of lines♫
♫Time is like a poem, romantic and sorrowful♫
♫Two hearts♫
♫Collide between dawn and dusk♫
♫The embrace came as a surprise♫
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫I want to keep you by my side♫
♫Through the obstacle of wind and rain♫
Stay still.
Don't move.
♫I want to be your moonlight♫
♫Accompany you until every dawn♫
♫How I wish♫
♫I could just forget the passage of time like this♫
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
You clearly did it on purpose.
♫May we never forget each other♫
♫There will always be a place for us to meet♫
♫I want to be with you forever♫
♫When our black hair turns grey♫
♫In this life♫
♫I'll only cherish you in my heart♫
My Lord.
Come on, Xing.
Sit down and have some tea.
Let's chat for a while.
What new rumors are there about me now?
There aren't any, really.
There are no rumors.
Isn't that right, My Lord?
It's just that
all of us
unanimously agree that
there's a dominatrix in our Ministry of Justice.
And this dominatrix
is extremely formidable.
She even dared to yell at White Ghost.
Unfortunately,
in the end,
she got
hung upside down on a horse
and paraded through the streets by the White Ghost.
As for women,
it's best for them to be
gentle,
kind,
courteous,
frugal,
and
yielding.
Lu Chuichui!
You're late again.
Not only are you late,
but you also look gloomy.
What were you up to yesterday?
Nothing much.
What kind of attitude is this?
Feng Gui.
My Lord.
Chen Huo'e was resurrected last night.
The Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau
had someone deliver the case file here
early this morning,
indicating this case...
On my way in,
Ji Fangming, who's in charge of receiving and reviewing case files,
gave this to me.
Give it to me.
It's said to be a case that was submitted
by Wannian County.
At Xuanping Pavilion in Wannian County,
a murder case occurred.
The victim was the wife of
a former official who had resigned and returned home,
Chen Shoujie.
Making a fuss over a woman's death.
According to you, Director Wu,
could it be that only men's lives and deaths
matter?
Are women's lives
not worthy of attention?
What did I say?
You married into the Shen family,
and your temper has grown, hasn't it?
Fine.
Forget I said anything.
Feng Gui.
Arrange for the constables to investigate.
My Lord. My Lord.
The coroner's report states
the victim was probably killed last night.
There appeared on her shoulder
a giant fire-scorched moth.
It's exactly the same
as the marks
[Chen Shoujie's Confession]
left on those victims
from Chen Huo'e murder cases from five years ago.
It's Chen Huo'e again.
Director Wu.
Please allow me to participate in the investigation of this case.
Since this matter is related to the case of
Chen Huo'e's resurrection,
it should be handed over to the Imperial Security Bureau
to be handled together.
That's right.
It's inappropriate for our Ministry of Justice
[File of Chen Shoujie's Wife's Case]
to get involved.
Right, right. It's inappropriate.
Although the Grand Commander is your husband,
in the Shen family, you're just
someone who gets beaten up.
When the White Ghost solves cases,
he won't take you along.
He won't.
Chief Censor has arrived.
Greetings, Lord Lai.
Lord Lai.
Although the White Ghost is unwilling to take you along,
I, Black Rakshasa,
would very much like to invite Miss Yan
to assist in the investigation together.
Director Wu.
Five years ago,
I was the one responsible for investigating
the Chen Huo'e case.
I've experienced
Yan Xing's investigative methods.
Since you're also interested
in the Chen Huo'e case this time,
why don't you
come work at my Imperial Investigation Department?
You could help me catch the real culprit. What do you say?
Thank you for your kind offer, Lord Lai.
But I'm just a minor scribe in the Ministry of Justice.
I only hope that in the future,
I can participate in the selection for female officials
and pass the exam for the position of Document Secretary.
I have no plans to work at another department.
Since you refuse to accept my goodwill, Mrs. Shen,
then...
Let's meet again another day.
Take care, Lord Lai.
Stop the carriage.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Mr. Han.
It's been a while since we last met.
Now that we've run into each other today,
do you still plan to avoid me?
I dare not, Your Highness.
Mr. Han, what's that supposed to mean?
Stand up and answer me.
Your Highness.
I am but a humble commoner.
I fear I might offend you, Your Highness.
Mr. Han, why are you saying such things?
Matters of the heart
cannot be forced.
Since your heart
already belongs to someone else,
I shall gladly step aside for your happiness.
This humble one is deeply grateful for your kindness, Your Highness.
Let's go.
Your Highness.